<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bertocq]]></title>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-03T18:48:33+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://bertocq.es/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alberto Calderon @bertocq]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bertocq@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ZTE Open unboxing]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/zte-open-unboxing/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-03T16:51:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/zte-open-unboxing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I heard about <a href="http://firefoxosguide.com/firefox-os/zte-open-to-launch-tomorrow-in-spain-venezuela-colombia-on-15th-july.html/" title="Movistar zte open launch">Movistar launching the ZTE Open</a> this week I rushed to the nearest Movistar shop to ask when they will receive and how many, but they didn&rsquo;t even know what Firefox OS was about!.</p>

<p>I had to show them my <a href="http://shop.geeksphone.com/en/3-phones" title="Geeksphone mobiles">Geeksphone Keon and Peak</a> and make a quick explanation about the origins and purpose of the new operative system. So they took my card to call me when the package arrived and maybe explain a bit more another day.</p>

<p>And today has been the day!!, they received only one unit and there was only another person waiting for it but I asked for it first luckyly.</p>

<p>Since I&rsquo;ll be using it for development only I chose the only-voice plan that costs 6€/month (it&rsquo;s the minimum) and for internet connection WiFi will be enough.</p>
]]></content>
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="firefox-os" />
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="mobile-dev" />
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="movistar" />
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="zte-open" />
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back on track]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/back-on-my-feet/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T22:25:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/back-on-my-feet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s has been a hell of a month, but finally difficulties all over. I have moved between 3 citys in 24 days, with all the logistics it involves (looking for rent houses, transporting?? our things, setting up internet and ligth contracts&hellip; etc..)</p>

<p>So we are finally stable and I can get back to business.</p>

<p>A month and 15 days ago I was in Bilbao and fui al firefos os event y conocí a un ídolo @soyjavi y pude charlar unos minutos con el, en el hackathon me encontré solo y reviví una vieja idea de app para lentillas y para mi sorpresa gané la categoría a la mejor app de ehealth con un Geeksphone peak!! More about it here=> Winning a hckathon of fierxox so</p>

<p>So I got an adrenaline rush and started developing dthe app, learning more about firefox os and finally bougth a Keon and got lucky with the review team
=>> Another post with all of this</p>

<p>A month ago I got involved in the review team of mozilla blabalbla</p>

<p>and now Im back to reviews, starting the second phase of the app development, with 2 more ideas and thinking of porting the app to android an ios just because i can and for fun
==>> A series of posts with the development stages (Find &amp; analize a problem, visualize &amp; design a solution, prototype &amp; develop the app, test &amp; pivot &amp; port)</p>

<p>Links links links linkssssss</p>
]]></content>
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="personal" />
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="projects" />
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello (Octopress) World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-24T01:32:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The hosting of my wordpress blog died less than a year ago, because I didn&rsquo;t have enough time and motivation to write.</p>

<p>So here I am, getting back on business, but this time with octopress and in english!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll start with some plugins and theme customizations in my spare time.</p>
]]></content>
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="github" />
    
      <category scheme="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/" term="octopress" />
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
