<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | BertoCQ]]></title>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-23T02:36:57+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://bertocq.es/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alberto Calderon Queimadelos @bertocq]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bertocq@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long time no see!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T00:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost two years has passed since my last post, and a lot happened that made me forgot about my blog: my family got bigger, we moved again 4 times until she landed a nice job (although not very stable), and months later I got another job on Web &amp; Mobile development in the same city (<a href="http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albacete">Albacete</a>).</p>

<p>I stayed 1 year and 4 months working at <a href="http://www.netberry.es/">Netberry</a>, it was good but I got stuck with PHP. And with &ldquo;stuck&rdquo; I mean that it sucked all my energy and didn&rsquo;t do any side projects or learning&hellip; just work &amp; trail running.</p>

<p>Anyway I enjoyed it, improved a lot my jQuery, learned about framework internals (we used a custom PHP framework built on top of <a href="http://framework.zend.com/">Zend</a>, some futile investigations about PHPExcel, SEPA data format form bank transfers and domiciliations&hellip;</p>

<p>Also did a cool project involving IndexedDB and Cache Manifest to make a web application work entirely offline in the web browser of a technician working on Solar and Eolic plants&hellip; I&rsquo;ll write about it soon.</p>

<p>On January her job crashed and we got lucky again, because she landed a 2 year job at Madrid, and I&rsquo;ll be again changing tracks on my carrer for good&hellip; Ruby here we go!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
