<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | BertoCQ]]></title>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-23T22:24:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://bertocq.es/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alberto Calderon Queimadelos @bertocq]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bertocq@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long time no see!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T00:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot has happened since my last post that made me completely forget the blog. My family got bigger with a girlfriend and a rescued greyhound, we moved 3 more times until she landed a nice job in Albacete, until this January that she got an awesome opportunity at Madrid.</p>

<h1>Netberry</h1>

<p>In albacete I got a job on Web &amp; Mobile development at <a href="http://www.netberry.es/">Netberry</a> during the year and half that we stayed. It was a good place to work, with a nice family feeling among the co-workers.</p>

<p>I improved a lot my jQuery, learned about framework internals (we used a custom PHP framework built on top of <a href="http://framework.zend.com/">Zend</a>), some custom scripts with PHPExcel and SEPA data format form bank transfers and domiciliations&hellip; worked on some cool and big projects, patched legacy code&hellip; but definetly got tired of PHP.</p>

<p>Also I built a cool project involving IndexedDB and Cache Manifest to make a web application work entirely offline in the browser, so a technician working on a Solar or Eolic plant without connection could still use it&hellip; I&rsquo;ll write about it soon.</p>

<h2>Whats next?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m pretty tired of PHP and its environment, so since I&rsquo;m in Madrid and there are plenty of job offers for diverse positions, I&rsquo;ll finally give an opportunity for Ruby to change my career and have fun again at work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back on track]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/back-on-track/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T22:25:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/back-on-track</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s has been a hell of a month, but finally difficulties all over. I have moved between 3 citys in 24 days, with all the logistics it involves (looking for rent houses, transporting our things, setting up internet, gas, water and ligth contracts&hellip;). Emancipation is hard, but this was a master class!</p>

<p>So we are finally stable and I can get back to business.</p>

<p>Meanwhile I was accepted as in the Firefox App Review Team, and wrote down two more ideas that hopefully will transform in nice FirefoxOS apps one day. Also bought an GeeksPhone Keon so the Peak doesn&rsquo;t feel alone anymore.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-E1_nLO2WYsA/UdSLH9p9LBI/AAAAAAAAEBA/AyvUTnm36jE/w510-h680-no/2013-06-02+13.17.29.jpg">https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-E1_nLO2WYsA/UdSLH9p9LBI/AAAAAAAAEBA/AyvUTnm36jE/w510-h680-no/2013-06-02+13.17.29.jpg</a>" width="500" title="&lsquo;Geeksphone Keon and Peak&rsquo; &lsquo;Geeksphone Keon and Peak&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
