<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | BertoCQ]]></title>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-28T23:53:31+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://bertocq.es/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alberto Calderon Queimadelos @bertocq]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bertocq@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long time no see!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T00:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot has happened since my last post, that made me completely forget the blog. My family got bigger with a girlfriend and a rescued greyhound, we moved 3 more times until she landed a nice job in Albacete for 2 years, and this January she got an awesome opportunity at Madrid that will last 4-5 years at least.</p>

<h2>Netberry &amp; PHP tiredness</h2>

<p>During the year and half that we stayed in Albacete I got a job on Web &amp; Mobile development at <a href="http://www.netberry.es">Netberry</a>. It was a good place to work, with a nice family feeling among the co-workers, and made some great friends.</p>

<p>In my first project I built a web application that works <a href="http://diveintohtml5.info/offline.html">entirely offline</a> in the browser, so a technician working on a solar or eolic plant without connection could still use it. I’ll write about it soon… but basically used <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/IndexedDB/">IndexedDB</a> for the data, Javascript for the logic and <a href="http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cache_manifest_in_HTML5">Cache Manifest</a> to let the files persist without internet.</p>

<p>Also improved a lot my <a href="https://jquery.com">jQuery</a> and Javascript, learned about framework internals (we used a custom PHP framework built on top of <a href="http://framework.zend.com">Zend</a>)), some custom scripts with <a href="https://phpexcel.codeplex.com">PHPExcel</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_Euro_Payments_Area">SEPA</a> data format form bank domiciliations… worked on some cool and big projects, patched legacy code at others… Even got the opportunity to evangelize about <a href="http://git-scm.com">Git</a>, <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com">SublimeText</a> and <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/phpstorm">PhpStorm</a>.</p>

<p>But definetly got tired of PHP and it’s environment after more than 10 years dealing with passing frameworks, customs CMS’s and Wordpress/Drupal/etc…</p>

<h2>So whats next? Ruby!!</h2>

<p>Since we are living in Madrid and there are plenty of job offers for diverse positions, I’ll finally give <a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org">Ruby</a> a solid chance to change my career and have fun again at work.</p>

<p>Many years has passed since I first tried it, and even got a good chance to work with <a href="http://rubyonrails.org">RoR</a> (although life got in the way)… but third time’s the charm, because this time I got everything on place.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back on track]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/back-on-track/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T22:25:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/back-on-track</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s has been a hell of a month, but finally difficulties all over. I have moved between 3 citys in 24 days, with all the logistics it involves (looking for rent houses, transporting our things, setting up internet, gas, water and ligth contracts&hellip;). Emancipation is hard, but this was a master class!</p>

<p>So we are finally stable and I can get back to business.</p>

<p>Meanwhile I was accepted as in the Firefox App Review Team, and wrote down two more ideas that hopefully will transform in nice FirefoxOS apps one day. Also bought an GeeksPhone Keon so the Peak doesn&rsquo;t feel alone anymore.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-E1_nLO2WYsA/UdSLH9p9LBI/AAAAAAAAEBA/AyvUTnm36jE/w510-h680-no/2013-06-02+13.17.29.jpg">https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-E1_nLO2WYsA/UdSLH9p9LBI/AAAAAAAAEBA/AyvUTnm36jE/w510-h680-no/2013-06-02+13.17.29.jpg</a>" width="500" title="&lsquo;Geeksphone Keon and Peak&rsquo; &lsquo;Geeksphone Keon and Peak&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
