<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal, | BertoCQ]]></title>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bertocq.es/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-23T22:41:04+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://bertocq.es/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alberto Calderon Queimadelos @bertocq]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bertocq@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long time no see!]]></title>
    <link href="http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T00:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bertocq.es/blog/long-time-no-see</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A lot has happened since my last post that made me completely forget the blog. My family got bigger with a girlfriend and a rescued greyhound, we moved 3 more times until she landed a nice job in Albacete, until this January that she got an awesome opportunity at Madrid.</p>

<h2>Netberry</h2>

<p>In albacete I got a job on Web &amp; Mobile development at <a href="http://www.netberry.es/">Netberry</a> during the year and half that we stayed. It was a good place to work, with a nice family feeling among the co-workers.</p>

<p>In my first project I built a web application that works entirely <a href="http://diveintohtml5.info/offline.html">offline</a> in the browser, so a technician working on a Solar or Eolic plant without connection could still use it&hellip; I&rsquo;ll write about it soon, but basically used <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/IndexedDB/">IndexedDB</a> for the data, Javascript the logic and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cache_manifest_in_HTML5">Cache Manifest</a> to let the files persist without internet.</p>

<p>Also improved a lot my jQuery and Javascript, learned about framework internals (we used a custom PHP framework built on top of <a href="http://framework.zend.com/">Zend</a>), some custom scripts with <a href="https://phpexcel.codeplex.com/">PHPExcel</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_Euro_Payments_Area">SEPA</a> data format form bank domiciliations&hellip; worked on some cool and big projects, patched legacy code at others&hellip; but definetly got tired of PHP and it&rsquo;s environment after more than 10 years.</p>

<h2>Whats next?</h2>

<p>Since I&rsquo;m in Madrid and there are plenty of job offers for diverse positions, I&rsquo;ll finally give an opportunity for <a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org">Ruby</a> to change my career and have fun again at work.</p>

<p>Many years has passed since I first tried it, and even got a second chance to work at <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">RoR</a> (although life got in the way)&hellip; but third time&rsquo;s the charm, because this time I got everything on place.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
